bantamlive.com 2012-12-29

# Privacy Statement - Constant Contact ®

Effective January 2, 2012   

At Constant Contact, we respect and protect the privacy of our customers and those who use our website and our products and services. This privacy statement provides details about how your personal information is collected and used. Personal information is any information that identifies you or would enable someone to contact you, such as your name, email address, phone number and other non-public information that is associated with the foregoing. This privacy statement applies to the Constant Contact website, products and services that are located in the roving.com and constantcontact.com domains and any other sites owned or operated by Constant Contact (the "Sites"). Constant Contact, Inc. is located at 1601 Trapelo Road, Waltham, MA 02451. 

  * Information Collection and Use by Us
  * Security and Privacy
  * Sharing of Information
  * Cookies and Web Beacons
  * Online Advertising
  * Choice/Opt-out
  * Access to Personal Information
  * Refer a Friend
  * Third Party Links and Information Collection and Use by Our Customers
  * Children
  * International Use
  * Accountability
  * Notification of Changes

## Information Collection and Use by Us

We are the sole owner of information collected on the Sites, except for contact lists and content that you provide to us in connection with your use of our products and services. We will not sell, share, or rent this information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this privacy statement. We may obtain information that is provided during any voluntary or mandatory registration process, online payment transaction, request for technical support, when you call or email us, or when you visit our Sites. We collect information only as necessary to fulfill the purposes set forth in this privacy statement. 

Our Sites offer several opportunities for visitors to register for promotional and informational mailings, online webinars and resources, and to evaluate our products and services. These registration forms enable users to opt-in to our mailing lists and require users to give contact information (such as name and email address). Notice is given at the point of collection to enable users to choose whether or not they consent to the usage terms. Those who have signed up for future mailings and subsequently wish to withdraw their participation may opt-out of receiving future mailings at any time (see the "Choice/Opt-out" section below). We may use this information to provide you with requested information or products or services, to tailor the presentation of the Sites or products or services to you, to facilitate your movement through the Sites or your use of our products and services, to improve our products and services and do a better job of marketing them, or to communicate with you. 

Our Sites also offer opportunities for visitors to purchase our products and services. Payment information, including credit card data, is used only for the purpose of facilitating payment for the transaction with respect to which the information was provided. 

You acknowledge and expressly agree that we may obtain additional information about you that we collect from other sources, such as information you provide at seminars or to our partners, information that is publicly available or that you consent to us receiving from third parties. With your consent, we may access certain information from a third party social networking site ("SNS"). The information you allow us to access varies by SNS, and it is affected by the privacy settings you establish at the SNS. When you consent to the SNS sharing information with us, the SNS may know that you have a relationship with us. You can control and find out more about these privacy settings at the applicable SNS. We may use this information to provide you with our products and services, to improve our products and services and do a better job of marketing them, or to communicate with you. 

We also keep track of activity on our Sites using log files stored on our web servers. We collect information, such as IP address, browser type and version, and pages you view. We also keep track of how you got to our Sites and any links you click on to leave our Sites. We may gather information about any device or other method of communication you use to interact with the Sites. We also gather aggregated tracking information regarding overall usage of the Sites and the products and services, including tallies of page views and click-through activity and the number of messages sent using our products or services. We may use this information to assist us in offering you a personalized Web experience, to assist you with technical support, to diagnose problems with our server, in connection with our security program, to administer our website, to improve our products and services and do a better job of marketing them, or to tailor our product and service offerings to you. 

We may monitor or record any of your telephone conversations with us for quality control purposes, for purposes of training our employees and for our own protection. 

We obtain information that is provided by you on our public forums, including the Constant Contact Community and Constant Contact Marketplace. Your posts may remain even after you deactivate your account. Contributions to any of our public communities are considered public and non-confidential by us and are not treated as proprietary information or personal information covered by this privacy statement. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at [support@constantcontact.com](mailto:support@constantcontact.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why. We will also obtain any information that you provide to us in connection with the use of our products and services (such as contact lists, content and phone numbers for your subscribers who take advantage of our Text-to-Join feature). We acknowledge your ownership rights in such contact lists, content and phone numbers. We will never sell or rent your contact lists, content or phone numbers to anyone without your permission, and will never use your contact lists, content or phone numbers for internal marketing or promotional purposes or for any purpose other than providing our products and services. 

Back to Top

## Security and Privacy

We employ reasonable technical, administrative and physical safeguards to protect the confidentiality and security of your personal information. We use industry-recognized technical safeguards, such as firewalls, and have adopted and implemented security procedures to protect your information from loss, misuse or unauthorized alteration. When we collect financial account information, such as credit card numbers, we protect its transmission through the use of encryption such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol. Notwithstanding our efforts, we cannot guarantee absolute or unqualified protection of this information given the open nature and resulting instability of the Internet and World Wide Web, and we make no representations or warranties as to the effectiveness of our security and assume no liability for security breaches or any failure in the security of your computer equipment, your internet service provider or other networks and communications providers. 

Back to Top

## Sharing of Information

We will never sell or rent your personal information to third parties for their use without your consent. 

If you accessed one of our Sites or any of our products or services through or in connection with a solicitation from one of our partners, we may share your information with the partner and the partner may share related information with us. Occasionally, we enter into contracts with third parties so that they can assist us in servicing you (for example, providing customer service). Our contracts with such third parties prohibit them from using any of your personal information for any purpose beyond the purpose for which they were engaged, including for their own purposes, and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of the information we provide to them. We may also share non-personally identifying information in the aggregate with third parties, such as the media, industry observers, potential customers or partners. For example, we may disclose the number of users that have been exposed to, or clicked on, our Sites or evaluated or purchased our products and services. 

If we are involved in a merger, acquisition, a sale of all or a substantial portion of our assets, or other similar transaction, your information may be transferred as part of that transaction. We will notify you by email and/or a prominent notice on our website of any such transaction and the choices you may have regarding your information. 

Lastly, we may disclose your personal information to courts, law enforcement authorities and/or other relevant third parties, such as internet service providers, when such disclosure is necessary or advisable, in our sole discretion, to conduct an investigation, respond to a third party or law enforcement subpoena or court order, bring legal action or pursue other relief when you or a third party are or may be: (a) violating our terms and conditions of use; (b) causing injury or other harm to, or otherwise violating our property or other legal rights, or those of other users or third parties; or (c) violating federal, state, local, or other applicable law. This disclosure may include transferring information to the U.S. and outside the European Economic Area. 

Back to Top

## Cookies and Web Beacons

We use a variety of technologies on our Sites. Among these are cookies: a text-only string of information that a website transfers to the cookie file of the browser on your computer so that the website can remember your browser in the future. A cookie will typically contain the name of the domain from which the cookie has come, the "lifetime" of the cookie, and a value, usually a unique number. When you visit our Sites, open our email, encounter our services online (including on one of our customer's websites), or click on one of our banner ads or videos, we or an authorized third party may send you a cookie. 

Cookies may be used by us in many ways: they allow us to verify the login status of customers using products or services linked directly with our Sites, track point of entry to point of registration for those users participating in our affiliate signup programs, and track and measure the success of a particular marketing campaign, and to provide you with more relevant content. Cookies also allow us to track overall site usage and determine areas users prefer, as well as enable us to make your visit to our website easier by recognizing you when you return and help to provide you with a customized experience. 

Information gathered through usage of a cookie is not linked to any personal identifying information, unless you become a trial or paying customer of ours. Once you submit personally identifiable information on our Sites (for example, by signing up to be a trial or paying customer of ours or by signing up for a seminar or white paper), we may link such information with cookies or other identifiers that are associated with your visit(s) to our Sites. You have the ability to accept or decline cookies by modifying the settings in your browser. If you choose to disable cookies, you may still use our Sites; however, you may have limited access to some areas within our Sites or a different experience. For more information on how to manage cookies in your web browser, see [http://www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/). We also provide you with an option to opt-out of receiving certain cookies associated with our online advertising (see the "Online Advertising" section below). 

Some of our web pages, emails, and other online content may contain electronic images provided by us or authorized third parties known as web beacons, also known as single-pixel GIFs, which are invisible graphical images. These web beacons allow us to count users who have visited our Sites, seen our ads, or opened our email, and to track whether messages are shared using our social share features and, once shared, whether these messages are opened by the recipient. In addition, when you click on a link in an email, we record this individual response to allow us to customize our offerings to you. Web beacons collect only limited information, such as a cookie identifier, time and date of a page being viewed, and a description of the page on which the web beacon resides. Web beacons cannot be declined when delivered using a regular web page, but they can be refused when delivered by email. If you do not wish to receive web beacons by email, you will need to disable HTML images or refuse HTML (select Text only) emails via your email software. 

We may from time to time engage third parties to track and analyze information about your activity on our Sites, including data gathered by cookies or web beacons. For example, we use Adobe® SiteCatalyst® and Adobe® Test&Target® to improve our web site performance, to run tests on the effectiveness of our Sites and marketing efforts and to improve user experience. For more information on the SiteCatalyst service and privacy policy, see <http://www.omniture.com/en/privacy/visualsciences/policy>, and for more information on the Test&Target service and privacy policy, see <http://www.omniture.com/en/privacy/product>. All such data is only used for the purposes described in this section. 

We may share non-personally identifying information with third parties, such as the media, industry observers or potential customers or partners. 

Back to Top

## Online Advertising

We also use pixels, or transparent GIF files, to help manage online advertising. These GIF files are provided by our ad management partners and enable our partners to recognize a unique ad impression cookie on your Web browser, which in turn enables us to learn which advertisements bring users to our Sites. With both cookies and web beacons, the information that we collect and share is anonymous and not personally identifiable. We give all Internet users the choice to opt-out of receiving our ad impression cookie. If you opt out, your web browser will be associated with a generic "opt-out" cookie, which will prevent us from associating any non-personally identifying information with your browser. Our "opt-out" cookie has no expiration date. Keep in mind that participating in our opt-out program does not prevent you from seeing our online ads; instead, information about the online ads we serve to you will not be recorded. If you wish to opt-out of receiving this cookie, see <http://www.constantcontact.com/opt-out-info.jsp>. 

Our ad management partners include Mediaplex, Google Inc., Advertising.com, LinkedIn Corporation, ShareThis and Facebook. For more information about our ad management partners, including information about how to opt-out of these technologies, visit the privacy policies on their websites. 

Back to Top

## Choice/Opt-out

Our Anti-Spam Policy tolerates only permission-based email, see <http://www.constantcontact.com/uidocs/CCSpamPolicy.jsp>. You may choose to opt-out or select your email preferences when you sign-up for our email lists. You always have the opportunity to opt-out or change preferences by following a link in the footer of all non-transactional email messages sent by us or by emailing us at [support@constantcontact.com](mailto:support@constantcontact.com). In addition, anyone receiving emails from us on behalf of our customers always has the opportunity to opt-out of email messages by using the opt-out link included in the link in the footer of the message. If you believe that you have received an unsolicited commercial email from us on behalf of any of our customers, you may report it to us at [abuse@constantcontact.com](mailto:abuse@constantcontact.com). 

Some communications (for example, important account notifications and billing information) are considered transactional and are necessary for all of our customers. You must cancel your Constant Contact account to unsubscribe from these communications. To cancel your Constant Contact account, please email us at [support@constantcontact.com](mailto:support@constantcontact.com). 

To manage the information we receive about you from an SNS or any other third party, you will need to follow the instructions from that party for updating your information and changing your privacy settings. The information we collect is covered by this privacy statement and the information the third party collects is subject to such third party's privacy practices. Privacy choices you have made on any third party site will not apply to our use of the information we have collected directly through our applications. 

Back to Top

## Access to Personal Information

You can update your account information, including your organizational information and email address, by logging in and then clicking on the My Settings tab. Account information, such as your username and password, can be changed by logging in and then clicking on the My Account link at the top of page. The My Account page is also where you can manage product subscriptions and billing information, such as your credit card number. If you would like to deactivate your account or obtain further information about or access to your personal information, you can do so by contacting customer support by email at [support@constantcontact.com](mailto:support@constantcontact.com) or by telephone at (866) 289-2101 if you are located in the U.S. or (781) 472-8140 if you are located outside of the U.S. 

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at [support@constantcontact.com](mailto:support@constantcontact.com). We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements. 

Back to Top

## Refer a Friend

If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our Sites or our products and services, we will ask you for your friend's email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit our website. We retain this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of our referral program. Such referrals may not be permissible in all situations or in all jurisdictions. You acknowledge and agree that you are solely responsible for compliance with any applicable laws in this regard. Your friend may contact us at [support@constantcontact.com](mailto:support@constantcontact.com) to request that we remove this information from our database. 

Back to Top

## Third Party Links and Information Collection and Use by Our Customers

Some of our Sites provide links to third-party websites, such as those of our business partners, online advertising partners, SNSs and payment processors. While on these sites, we or these third parties may collect information about you. In addition, you may be asked to provide certain personal information or credit card information to our customers in connection with their use of our products and services, such as when you respond to a survey or register or pay for an event, or otherwise. 

Because we do not control the information policies or practices of these third parties or our customers, you should review their privacy policies to learn more about how they collect and use personally identifiable information. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of any third parties or our customers. 

Back to Top

## Children

Our Sites and our products and services are not directed to persons under 13. We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13. If a parent or guardian becomes aware that his or her child has provided us with personal information without such parent or guardian's consent, he or she should contact us. If we become aware that a child under 13 has provided us with personal information, we will delete such information from our files. 

Back to Top

## International Use

We are headquartered in the United States of America. Personal information may be accessed by us or transferred to us in the United States or to our affiliates, business partners, merchants, or service providers elsewhere in the world. By providing us with personal information, you consent to this transfer. We will protect the privacy and security of personal information according to this privacy statement, regardless of where it is processed or stored, however you explicitly acknowledge and consent to the fact that personal information stored or processed in the United States will be subject to the laws of the United States, including the ability of governments, courts or law enforcement or regulatory agencies of the United States to obtain disclosure of your personal information. 

For the purposes of European Directive 95/46/EC and applicable national implementing laws in your jurisdiction, with respect to your data, we are a data controller and with respect to your customer's information, we are a data processor. 

Back to Top

## Accountability

We are a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. TRUSTe is an independent organization whose mission is to build users' trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the use of fair information practices. Because we want to demonstrate our commitment to your privacy, we have agreed to disclose our information practices and have our privacy practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe. 

If you have questions or concerns regarding this privacy statement, you should first contact us as described below. If you do not receive acknowledgement of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should contact TRUSTe at [http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint&url=http://www.constantcontact.com](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint&url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.constantcontact.com). TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with us to resolve your concerns. 

We comply with the U.S. - EU and U.S. - Swiss Safe Harbor frameworks as set forth by the Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use and retention of data from the European Union and the Swiss Confederation. Information regarding the U.S. - E.U. and U.S. Swiss Safe Harbor Framework can be found at: <http://export.gov/safeharbor>. 

We have designated our Privacy Manager to oversee our compliance with applicable privacy laws. Questions and inquiries concerning your privacy may be directed by email to [privacy@constantcontact.com](mailto:privacy@constantcontact.com) or write us: 

Constant Contact, Inc.  
1601 Trapelo Road  
Waltham, MA 02451  
Attention: Privacy Manager 

Back to Top

## Notification of Changes

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we decide to change this privacy statement in any material way, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on the Constant Contact website so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. For major changes in how we use personally identifying data, we will provide advance notice. In all cases, your continued use of any Site or our products and services or constitutes consideration and your binding acceptance to any such changes. 

Back to Top
